Kingsley Ofosu

kingsleyofosu@yahoo.com

+ [233] 201-694-902 / 541-424-292



www.linkedin.com/in/kingsleyofosu



www.kingsleyofosu.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a results-driven software developer with several years of experience in desktop and web applications development. I also have a strong background in database administration.

I am an expert in devising tailored solutions to assist businesses achieve their goals in a variety of industries and a cyber security enthusiast.

I strongly believe that, developing good applications for organizations always contribute to putting those organizations ahead. I am flexible enough to work in a team, but also enjoy working independently. I also possess superb communication skills.

SKILLS

- Frameworks and Languages -JavaScript, Node.js, Angular, Ionic, C#, VB.NET and SOL.
- Up to date knowledge of HTML5 and
- Web Technologies and Tools -Docker, Git, Jira, Confluence, **Jenkins**
- Version Control Github, Bitbucket
- Development Environments Microsoft Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code.
- Data Stores MS SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL and MongoDB.
- Operating Systems Windows, macOS and Linux.

- Troubleshooting computer hardware.
- Setting up, Configuring and troubleshooting of Basic LAN's.
- Installing and maintaining computer operating systems.
- Debugging and strong problemsolving skills.
- Setting up, Configuring and Installing of PC's and Printers.
- Sales and Marketing.
- **Financial Accounting**

EXPERIENCE

Vodafone Ghana

Accra, Ghana

Application Developer

March, 2020 - Present

ThinkWell Solutions Company Limited

CEO, Software Developer/Database Administrator

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana

- January, 2014 Present
- Designing, coding, debugging, testing and maintaining of Web/Desktop Applications.
- Designing, implementing and maintaining database for applications.
- Ensuring all applications meet the Software Requirement Specification.
- Testing applications developed by other development teams.
- Copyediting content for websites.
- Monitoring website and platform performance.
- Managing the hosting environment for websites and applications.
- Conducting training sessions for clients on the use of developed systems.

NATIONAL HEALTH INSURANCE SCHEME

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana September, 2013 – August, 2014

National Service Personnel

- Educating potential members on the importance of the scheme.
- Registration of new members to the scheme.
- Entering membership data and generating temporary cards for members.
- Assist in vetting of claims submitted by the scheme's accredited health facilities.

EDUCATION

Catholic University College of Ghana

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana September, 2009 – August, 2013

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Google Africa Developer Scholarship Program with Andela and Pluralsight

Mobile Web Specialist

May, 2019 – December, 2019

Pluralsight, Inc.

Used pluralsight.com, an amazing online education platform, to take courses offered by subject-matter experts, to acquire knowledge and skills in web development and cyber security.

• Developed a familiarity, solidified and enhanced my skills in JavaScript plus Node.js, Angular, HTML5 and CSS3.

- CompTIA Network+ courses Developed a familiarity with networking concepts, operations and procedures.
- CompTIA Security+ courses Developed a familiarity with how to install and configure systems to secure applications, networks and devices.
- Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP) courses Acquired the foundational knowledge needed to effectively design and manage the security of an organization.